Welcome to the first episode of the
Manufacturing Foundation series.
Today, you'll explore the bill of
materials, one of the core elements of
manufacturing.
The bill of materials,
also called BOM, is the list that
defines [music]
the components required to produce an
item.
Let's explore an example.
Once we open an item card,
>> [music]
>> we can scroll to the replenishment tab.
You can see [music] that the item can be
replenished in three different ways,
through purchase, a production order, or
an assembly.
Purchase is for items you buy and use or
sell without processing. For those that
are processed in your facilities, you
choose production order or assembly.
Notice that both define a BOM field.
So, what's the difference?
Assembly is used for straightforward
processes, simple labor-only work.
Choose production order when you need
multi-step operations, machine centers,
or capacity planning.
Let's open the production BOM.
The airpod is replenished using a
production order, where all components
required to build it are listed.
The quantity required is listed, but
also allowing you to use formulas for
standardized units of measure.
BOM acts [music] as the recipe and
drives material planning, consumption,
and costing.
You can add, remove, and reorganize the
columns shown in the line section as you
need.
A well-structured BOM helps you plan
materials accurately, reduce shortages,
and keep production running smoothly.
For each of the [music] items listed on
the bill of materials, you can see where
it is used using the where used action.
Let's explore another [music] product's
BOM, the Air Pod Light.
This new product is created by copying
the Air Pod's BOM and removing the
warming plate.
Few special fields worth mentioning.
The Air Pod Light contains two reservoir
assembly items, an item and a production
BOM.
The item version of reservoir assembly
has an ending date of 1st of June,
[music] when the production BOM version
starts being used.
This allows us to change an item without
major [music] alterations.
From the 1st of June, any Air Pod Light
will be produced [music] using the
phantom BOM instead of picking the
pre-produced item.
For more complex [music] modifications,
you can define new versions and their
starting date, so that production will
pick the correct production BOM.
Each version has its own list of
components.
If you want to see how they vary, you
can use the production BOM version
comparison, where the components are
listed for each of the versions of a
single [music] production BOM.
For version two and three, we can see
that we first kept the switch [music]
and removed the on-off light, but for
version three, we also removed the
switch.
Let's explore how the bill of materials
work from a production order by creating
one.
This production order is for the Air Pod
Light.
Let's say we need 50 units and that they
are due for the 1st of June.
Selecting the due date [music] allow us
to have an accurate capacity and
inventory planning.
Once those fields are defined, we can
refresh the production order to
automatically populate the order lines
[music] with components and routings.
This order is picking the base version
as no version code is shown.
Let's explore what happens if [music] we
change our due date and refresh the
order again.
Now we see the version two, which we can
also manually change to another [music]
if we want to make an exception.
The components action [music] allow us
to explore which are the items required
for the production of each product line.
An accurate bill of material definition
[music] improves cost visibility and
gives you better control over costs and
product changes as your [music] business
evolves.
In the next episode, you'll explore
routings, which define how the product
is made.
Together, your BOMs and the routings
form the core of efficient and
predictable manufacturing.
See you next time.